<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | John Buckeridge</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©{currentYear} by John Buckeridge</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:03:47 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/logo-scattering1.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD position available</title>
      <link>/post/nov2019_phd_ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/nov2019_phd_ad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I now have a PhD position available, starting in early 2020. Come join me at LSBU School of Engineering to investigate the electronic and optical properties of semiconductors using materials modelling techniques! The PhD studentship will involve developing and applying methodology to treat the interactions between electrons, phonons and photons in semiconductors used in energy and microelectronic devices. The aim will be to use state-of-the-art techniques to calculate how electrons and defects interact in a range of different materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details are available at this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lsbu.ac.uk/research/research-degrees/scholarships&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;, where you will find a pdf with the full project description. There are other PhD studentships available at LSBU too, that you can find advertised there, which may be of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Occult Chemistry</title>
      <link>/post/nov2019_occult_chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/nov2019_occult_chemistry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently read the excellent book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philipball.co.uk/invisible-the-dangerous-allure-of-the-unseen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invisible&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Philip Ball. It was a fascinating read, packed full of information on myth, magic, philosophy and science. What really struck me was how much science of the 19th century was either driven by, or related to, investigations into the occult. We&amp;rsquo;re talking about the golden era of sceances, mediums, mystics and stage magicians. The great discoveries of the late 19th century: radio waves, x-rays and &amp;lsquo;cathode rays&amp;rsquo; (or electrons) all were &amp;lsquo;invisible&amp;rsquo;, and were often thought to be related to apparent psychic forces, ghosts and other paranormal phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing to look back at it all now with the benefit of hindsight and question how they could have believed this stuff. Particularly interesting was the work of Sir William Crookes, who was either a crank or a dupe (or maybe both, as Ball suggests). This is Crookes, inventor of the famous radiometer, which many will have encountered in secondary school science. It turns out that he invented this device to try measure invisible, psychic forces, and seemed to believe he had been successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pleased to learn about the book pictured here, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anandgholap.net/AB_CWL_Occult_Chemistry.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Occult Chemistry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Annie Beasant and C. W. Leadbeater, two &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theosophical_Society&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;theosophists&lt;/a&gt; who basically used their imagination to come up with diagrams of atoms, the structure of which were unknown at the time. In some cases, they came up with structures remarkably similar to the common pictures of atomic orbitals we use nowadays, but they also drew some amazingly complex geometrical shapes that are unlike anything I have seen before. I love that they just assumed they could use their minds to &amp;lsquo;discover&amp;rsquo; what atoms looked like! The book also contains a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anandgholap.net/images/oc-009.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;picture of the periodic table&lt;/a&gt; from a paper in the Proceedings of the Royal Society, read in 1898 that I quite like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invisible&lt;/em&gt; really indicates just how well scientific investigations are embedded within the sociological frameworks in which they operate. We like to think of science as being ultra-rational, beyond influence from mere human biases, but despite our best efforts it rarely is. Although the scientific method is designed to avoid such influences, its failure to do so (or the failure of its implementation, more precisely) is something we need to be aware of. I wonder what driving forces and theories for investigations into the &amp;lsquo;invisible&amp;rsquo; that science is concerned with now, will look as strange in 100 years as those of Crookes et al. in the late 1800s do today? Many-worlds interpretations? Dark energy? ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special issue in Crystals</title>
      <link>/post/oct2019_guest_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/oct2019_guest_editor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am the guest editor for a special issue in the journal &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/journal/crystals&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crystals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the topic of defects in semiconductors. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively broad topic, but hopefully will attract a diverse set of papers. Please submit if you have some suitable work as your paper will be in good company and should reach the correct audience! More info can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/journal/crystals/special_issues/defects_semiconductors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining London South Bank University as a lecturer</title>
      <link>/post/oct2019_lsbu_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/oct2019_lsbu_start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a busy September, full of childcare, getting projects into a fit state for publication, meetings, planning, backing up files and physical labour, I have completed my move to LSBU. I now have an office with a view! And quite a nice view too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been made very welcome here by all the staff. The location is nice, the students are friendly and there are plenty of opportunities for research collaborations within the School of Engineering. I have a shorter commute, which involves boris-biking from Waterloo. Very pleasant so far!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving UCL after over 8 years at the Department of Chemistry</title>
      <link>/post/sept2019_ucl_leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/sept2019_ucl_leaving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very sad to be leaving UCL after so long. I have made many friends here, got to be involved in a lot of great research projects, formed collaborations that I hope will last the rest of my career and enjoyed life in Bloomsbury. Lunch Punch in the gym will be missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had many leaving dos, as I left Richard&amp;rsquo;s group in 2018 and David&amp;rsquo;s in 2019. Many nice meals were had, as well as beers in the Housman Room and various pubs. The pic is from a meal in the local Greek restaurant when I left Richard&amp;rsquo;s group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
